(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] Now let's see the solution to the exercise.
We're going to do a lot of refactoring,
and here, the purpose is to move things
into their own components.
We want to allow every component
to subscribe to state changes independently
instead of passing data by using the props.
And same for any feature that we are passing,
like for the function that we pass as props.
This needs to be handled actually directly
from the components in order to respect
also the principle of single responsibility.
So anything related to the form
should be inside the form components.
So I'm going to take from line here all the way to line 49.
I'm going to cut and put it inside the form right here,
and I'm going to take also here,
because you see that this is no longer used.
I'm going to take this and add it to the form,
actually the ref as well, because we're going to use the ref
to access one node in the form, and I'm going to rephrase.
And I'm going to add it right here.
So we're going to need to make some changes.
You see the hooks right here.
We're going to need to add them to the scope.
So let's grab them from the App.js.
Let's take this.
And instead of using forwardRef,
you see that we were passing that as prop.
We're going to use useRef.
Anything related to the form from now on
is going to be handled directly in the form.
So I'm going to remove this and this as well.
And there is one trailing closing parenthesis
that I'm going to remove as well.
We don't need that.
Let's go back to App.js.
And I think I may have a few things missing,
which is this is visible.
That should be inside the form as well.
Let's try that.
And I think that this one, the check function,
that should be inside the list,
so we're going to take care of this afterwards
for the list components.
Let's try that.
So now the app is up and running.
We're going to see if we have anything missing.
So the onSubmit is already declared,
and that's because now we no longer need
to use the props inside the form.
So here, the goal is not to read the state from the props.
So I'm going to remove that.
And yes, in order to access the atoms,
it's going to be one level up,
because this one is available in this directory.
So we're going to need to access it one level higher.
And that's because for this,
because we have removed all of that we're going to remove now,
we no longer going to need to pass this as props,
so let's remove this.
We're going to leave this without any props.
Let's refresh.
itemsCount is another one that I should also add,
so which is a selector, so that is inside the form.
I'm going to make a reference to the selectors,
so let's grab it from here and add it here as well
to the scope of the form components.
And I'm going to make sure that here as well, we can access it.
Here we go. So it's back to normal.
So we can again, use our list.
Let's see if the form is working properly as well.
allItems is not defined, so let's just make sure
that this one is also added to the scope.
And that's because this one
should be also added to the form.
Okay, here we go.
That should be fine now.
New item, and excellent.
This is working just fine.
So now let's do the same.
We're going to refactor now the list components.
So step by step, actually, I'm going to take this
to make sure that this is added to the scope.
I'm going to go inside the list components
and make sure that I add this to the scope first.
Then let's go back to the App.js,
and I'm going to remove things step by step.
I'm going to remove them.
And for the check method,
it's going to be added to the list that's added here.
I need to use also the same hooks, set all and set list.
And actually, I just need set list,
which is use recall states only instead of using.
So I just need to update the state here.
Let's update.
And I no longer need here the props,
so I just need the check and all items.
So let's also grab, just like we have in the form,
I'm going to make sure that this is available here, like so.
And now that we have moved everything,
so let's remove also this from the list components,
so we no longer need the props, and this as well.
And you see that now the app component is much lighter.
Same here, no longer necessary, and this as well.
Let's try that.
Excellent, so it looks like this is working just fine.
I can add items, I can remove items,
cross items off the list, and also delete them all.
I can filter and display only the ones completed,
and also check to display them all.
Congratulations on completing the challenge.
You now have a better sense
of how to manage the application state
with the atomic approach.
With the Recoil library,
atoms are used as independent objects
containing a single source of the state.
It's like the state variables
with useState with the React API,
but with Recoil, the state variables
are not attached to one component only.
They act as independent pieces of state
that can be shared between components
and can be accessible everywhere,
and the benefits are multiple.
Less boilerplate code, a shorter and much simpler syntax,
a better separation of concerns
with a clean separation between where the state lives
and where the state is consumed.
And it is important to highlight
that the learning curve is quick and easy.
So this is one more reasons to get you excited
and motivated about working with Recoil.